globe-democrat.com 2014-12-18

# Privacy

When you use Paper.li and/or its affiliated applications (such as but not limited to Juice or Newsrooms), all together defined as the « Paper.li Service » (or « Paper.li », « Services » or « Service »), you provide Paper.li and SmallRivers with personally identifiable information (Your Paper.li Information). This Policy explains the information practices that apply to your Paper.li Information. This Policy does not apply to information collected by third party Web sites linked to or otherwise accessible from Paper.li. The information collected or received by third party services is subject to their own privacy policies.

## What information do we collect and store?

Globally, we collect and store the pertinent data needed to run the Paper.li Service. We may gather and process information about you, including (but not limited to) information in the following categories:

  * For Paper.li or Paper.li apps registered users (Paper.li Members): Identification data you provided us or the third party service you are using to log in to Paper.li (e.g. for Twitter: user name, location, user info, etc.);

  * For Paper.li readers (unregistered): Electronic identification data (addresses IP);

  * For email subscribers: email addresses;

  * For mobile users: operating system and location;

  * Survey result and usage information;

  * Traffic data (data processed for the purpose of the conveyance of Paper.li or the billing thereof, including, but not limited to, the number of views, location of viewers, user sharing actions, user interactions with the Twitter service if performed directly on Paper.li pages, etc.).

**_Cookies_** : Like many websites, we use "cookie" technology to collect additional website usage data and to improve our Services. A cookie is a small data file that is transferred to your computer's hard disk. Paper.li may use both session cookies and persistent cookies to better understand how you interact with our Services, to monitor aggregate usage by our users and web traffic routing on our services, and to customize and improve our Services. Most Internet browsers automatically accept cookies. **You can instruct your browser, by changing its settings, to stop accepting cookies or to prompt you before accepting a cookie from the websites you visit. However, some Services may not function properly if you disable cookies.**

## How do we use this information and for what purpose?

Our primary purpose in collecting information is to provide you with a safe, smooth, efficient, and customized experience. Paper.li and SmallRivers collect and process, or have third party service providers acting on SmallRivers' behalf collecting and processing, personal data relating to you, as permitted or necessary to:

  * Provide a rich browsing experience, and in particular to organize the content published on Paper.li pages or Paper.li Apps;

  * To customize the Paper.li Service with more relevant content, like tailored stories and suggestions for content to share;

  * To make ads delivery more relevant to you based on criteria like your activity on the Paper.li Service, and measure their performance;

  * To inform you about service updates and faults;

  * To verify your identity.

## To whom do we transfer this information?

Except as provided below, Paper.li and SmallRivers shall not sell, rent, trade or otherwise transfer Your Paper.li Information and/or traffic data to any third party without your explicit permission, unless it is obliged to do so under applicable laws or by order of the competent authorities.

In order to provide you with the Paper.li Service you have requested, SmallRivers may sometimes, if necessary, share your data with partner service providers and/or agents, and/or the third party banking organization or other providers of payment services.

Your information may be stored and processed in any country in which SmallRivers and selected partners maintain facilities, including outside of the EU. In this regard, or for purposes of sharing or disclosing data in accordance to the above, SmallRivers reserves the right to transfer information outside of your country. By using the Paper.li Service you consent to any such transfer of information outside of your country.

**Specific information about Email addresses:**

**Paper.li Members (registered with Paper.li):** SmallRivers uses your email address to contact you with Paper.li service updates, marketing and promotional material and newsletter alerts to the Service to which you are volontarly subscribed.

If you no longer wish to receive company communication from us, you can unsubscribe to these notifications anytime via the footer of the email or by updating your 'preferences' information under your account settings.

If you no longer wish to receive newsletter alerts for a specific Paper.li paper or any other Paper.li Services to which you are subscribed, you can unsubscribe at any time via the footer of the email alert.

**Non-Paper.li Members (not registered with Paper.li):** SmallRivers uses your email address you have volontarly provided - and confirmed - to inform you when there is a new edition of the Paper.li paper to which you are subscribed.

If you no longer wish to receive these email notifications, you can unsubscribe at anytime via the footer of the email notification and your email address will be removed.

**Transmission of email address to Paper.li Pro publishers:**

The email address of both Paper.li Members and non Paper.li Members are transmitted to the publishers of PRO newspapers at the time a publisher upgrades his/her account to the Paper.li Pro service.

If you decide you no longer wish to receive email notifications to a paper you have subscribed to, you can unsubscribe at anytime via the footer of the email and your email address will be removed from the publisher's email list for that paper.

## How do we protect your personal information?

SmallRivers and its authorized partners shall take appropriate organizational and technical measures to protect your Paper.li Information and traffic data provided to us/them or collected by us/them, and shall not retain it any longer than permitted in order to perform its services or as required under relevant legislation. Your personal data can only be accessed by authorized employees of SmallRivers, SmallRivers authorized partners' employees needing to access this data to fulfill their given duties, or by Paper.li Pro Publishers in the case where you have a subscription to their online newspaper.

## Can this privacy statement be modified?

SmallRivers reserves the right to modify the provisions of this Privacy Statement if deemed necessary. We will inform you of these changes by publishing the revised Privacy Statement at www.paper.li. The revised Privacy Statement shall become immediately effective once published. You agree that your continued use of the Paper.li Service shall constitute your acceptance of the Privacy Statement.

## Can I object to my personal information being used and how to contact Paper.li?

You may object to the processing by SmallRivers of your personal data. However, in this case, SmallRivers may not be in a position to provide the Paper.li Service.

You can exercise your right to object to the processing detailed in the Privacy Statement by contacting SmallRivers at [legal(at)paper(dot)li](mailto:legal@paper.li).

## How long is my data kept by SmallRivers?

SmallRivers will retain your information for as long as is necessary to: (1) fulfill any of the purposes of the Paper.li Service or (2) comply with applicable legislation, regulatory requests and relevant orders from competent courts.

## Governing Law

By accessing the Paper.li Service, you and SmallRivers agree that all matters relating to your access to, or use of, Paper.li shall be governed by and construed in accordance with the laws of Switzerland, without giving effect to any principles of conflicts of law.

If you have any questions or concerns regarding this policy or the Paper.li service, please contact us at: [legal(at)paper(dot)li](mailto:legal@paper.li).
